Well, I told you that functions can do
three things. They can take some input,
they can do some work, and they can give
some output. Here on lines 13 through
16, we've done some work. Here on line
17, we've given some output. On lines 22
through 24, we've processed the result
of the function. But how do we take some
input? Well, um, let's look at how we
give input to another function. We're
going to call the alert function again.
And you'll notice in between these
parenthesis, we pass a message.
Um, well, let's try the prompt function.
Prompt. And this one tells us that I can
actually give it two pieces of
information, a message and a default.
So, I could say hello and I could say
autogenerated
text. And so, I can give this one two
pieces of information.
But notice how I did that. I gave it one
piece of information and then I put a
comma. and then I give it a second piece
of information. Well, let's see if we
could do that with our function. So, I'm
going to delete those two things and let
me just give it two numbers. I'm going
to give it 12 and 13. Let's save our
program and let's go run it.
Um,
all right.
So, we'll reload our page. Oh, let me
get rid of the break point.
and it says 30.
And if we look at our console, we don't
have any errors. We'll reload the page.
Said 30. And we'll go back over to our
code. Okay. So, it didn't use 12 and 13
as it input numbers. Why on earth was
that? Well, if you look at it, this
function is set up to use those two
numbers and return the results. But the
numbers it's using are the variables
that we just referenced on line 13 and
14.
um when we look at our function how to
call it we put two numbers here in
between the parenthesis and with a comma
separating them. So if we want to
receive that as input into our function
then we need to define it up here
between these parenthesis. So we can say
num one and num two.
So what we're doing is we're saying I
will take a number as an input and then
a comma and then I'm going to take
another number as an input. Because
we're taking inputs, we probably don't
need these lines of code anymore. So now
we we want our result to be the result
of num one
and num two.
So, we're saying when someone calls our
function, they're going to give us two
pieces of information separated by a
comma. Whoops. Separated by a comma. I
want to take those two pieces of
information, add them together, and
return the result. So now when we call
this, it should take the result of 12
and 13, return them, and then we'll
alert that. So if we save this
and we come over here, we get 25, which
is what we expected. But let's come over
here to our sources. We'll put a break
point on line 21 and we'll reload the
page. And it says, "Okay, we're about to
add two numbers." If we hit the next
button, we are now in our function. If
you hover over number one, you can see
it's 12. And why is it 12? Well, because
we put 12 in the first slot. This
function has no idea what we're going to
put in the slot. But it says whatever
they put in the first slot, call it num
one. So, they put 12 there, and we're
going to reference it by the name num
one. In num two, they put 13. And we're
two. How do we know it's num two?
Because they put it in the second
position. So down here when we called
it, because we put 12 first, it's num
one. Because we put 13 second, it's num
two. Now we're going to take the result
of those and add them. So num one is 12.
Num two is 13.
We hit next and our result is 25. We
return that result. And now our variable
called my result holds 25.